To change the world, she betrayed her country
Red Joan is a thriller, history film directed by Trevor Nunn.
London, England, May 2000.
The peaceful life of elderly Joan Stanley is suddenly disrupted when she is arrested by the British
Intelligence Service and accused of providing information to communist Russia during the forties.
Joan Elizabeth Stanley, played by Judi Dench.
Young Joan Elizabeth Stanley, played by Sophie Cookson.
Leo Galich, played by Tom Hughes.
Sonya Galich, played by Tereza Srbova.
Max, played by Stephen Campbell Moore.
Nick, played by Ben Miles.
Red Joan is a 2018 British spy drama film, directed by Trevor
Nunn, from a screenplay by Lindsay Shapero.
The film stars Sophie Cookson, Stephen Campbell Moore, Tom Hughes, Ben
Miles, Nina Sosanya, Tereza Srbova, and Judi Dench.
The film is based on a novel of the same name written by Jennie Rooney,
which was itself inspired by the life of Melita Norwood.
Norwood worked at the British Non-Ferrous Metals Research Association as a
secretary and supplied the Soviet Union with nuclear secrets.
The information that Norwood betrayed to the Soviets hastened the
pace at which they developed nuclear bomb technology.
Red Joan had its world premiere at the Toronto International Film Festival on 7 September
2018 and was released on 19 April 2019, by Lionsgate in the United Kingdom.
The film explores themes of london, england, based on
novel or book, atomic bomb, spy, cold war.
The tone is intense.